The next type of operator, a comparison operator,
compares two values. The comparisons include
equal to, not equal to, less than, greater than,
less than or equal to, or greater than or equal
to. Compared to assignments, comparisons happen
earlier in a sequence, but technically, the two
are not congruent, as an assignment cannot be part
of a comparison. We will cover comparisons in more
detail in the section on selecting operators, but
to see two examples in this 132-comparison file,
notice the print statements on lines 3 and 4,
first seeing if x equals y, and then if x is
greater than or equal to y. Comparisons return
either a True or False Boolean value. I will
run this code, and we see that the first value
is false as x does not equal y, and the second
value is true as x is greater than or equal to
y. The takeaway here is knowing that assignments
and comparisons happen at different times.
If you are looking for multiple comparisons,
let’s see what happens if we add greater than
two to the end of the comparison on line 4 and
then rerun the code. The second value is still
true. Another takeaway is that comparisons run
left to right in a line of code for a sequence.
If any part of a comparison is false, the entire
comparison is false. To demonstrate, I will change
the greater than symbol here, on line 4, to a less
than symbol and rerun the code. Both statements
are now false because, in the second statement,
x is greater than or equal to y, not less than or
equal to. Logically, most programmers want this
value returned because, for example, if someone is
trying to win a prize for conquering quests, that
person should not get said prize if any quests
are not conquered, meaning every condition needs
to be true for the premise of winning a prize to
be true. Knowing that any part of a comparison
statement being false will return false can help
one understand why a statement is false even
though parts of it are true. Then, one can adjust
the code as needed to fit the scope of an app.